Inventory of the Kingsley Davis Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Kingsley Davis Papers
1926-1981
83035
Davis, Kingsley, 1908-1997
55 manuscript boxes. (33 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, statistics, memoranda, reports, and printed matter, relating to international population changes, changes in family structure, and urbanization.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1908 August 20 Born, Tuxedo, Texas
1930 A.B. in English, University of Texas, Austin, Texas
1932 M.A. in Philosophy, University of Texas, Austin, Texas
1933 M.A. in Sociology, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts
1934-1936 Instructor, Sociology, Smith College, Massachusetts
1936 Ph.D., Sociology, Harvard University
1936-1937 Assistant Professor, Sociology, Clark University, Massachusetts
1937-1942 Associate Professor and Chairman, Pennsylvania State University
1942-1944 Visiting Research Associate, Office of Population Research, Princeton University, New Jersey, and Chairman, Pennsylvania State University
1942-1948 Associate Professor, Anthropology and Sociology, Princeton University
1944-1945 Associate Professor, Public Affairs, Princeton University
1944-1948 Research Associate, Princeton University
1948-1955 Professor, Sociology, Graduate Faculty of Political Science, Columbia University, New York
1949 Author, Modern American Society: Readings in the Problems of Order and Change
1950 Author, Corrientes Demográficas Mundiales
1951 Author, The Population of India and Pakistan
1955-1970 Professor, Sociology, University of California, Berkeley
1956-1977 Chairman, International Population and Urban Research, University of California, Berkeley
1958 Author, A Crowding Hemisphere: Population Change in the Americas
1961-1963 Chairman, Department of Sociology, University of California, Berkeley
1963 Author, Future Demographic Growth of the San Francisco Bay Area
1964 Author, The Place of Latin America in World Demographic History
1969 Author, World Urbanization, 1950-1970
1973 Author, Cities: Their Origin, Growth, and Human Impact: Readings from Scientific American
1980 Author, A Structural Analysis of Kinship: Prolegomena to the Sociology of Kinship
1970-1976 Ford Professor, Sociology and Comparative Studies, University of California, Berkeley
1976-1977 Ford Professor, Emeritus, University of California, Berkeley (recalled)
1977-1992 Distinguished Professor, Sociology, University of California, Los Angeles
1985 Author, Contemporary Marriage: Comparative Perspectives on a Changing Institution
1987 Author, Below-Replacement Fertility in Industrial Society: Causes, Consequences, Policies
1989 Author, Population and Resources in a Changing World: Current Readings
1991 Author, Resources, Environment, and Population: Present Knowledge, Future Options
1981-1992 Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution, Stanford University
1992-1997 Emeritus, Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution, Stanford University
1997 February 27 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The Kingsley Davis Papers, acquired in 1983, consist of correspondence, memoranda, notes, printed matter, reports, statistics, and speeches and writings, relating to international population changes, changes in family structure, and urbanization. Davis used some of this material as research materials for his numerous books on urbanization and population growth.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Family.; Population.; Urbanization.
Container List
- "The Role of Urbanization in the Development Process," paper to be presented, Sixth Rehovot Conference on Urbanization and Development, Israel, 1971 August 16-24. (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Correspondence only
- Bowker, Albert H., 1972 (Folder 1: 2)
- Professional business, undated (Folder 1: 3)
- Department of Demography, University of California, Berkeley, 1972-1976 (Folder 1: 4)
- Home file, 1973-1976. (Folder 1: 5-7)
  Correspondence with various professional organizations
- Copies of correspondence, 1973-1974 (Folder 1: 8)
- Urbanization--Monograph. Correspondence, 1951-1960 (Folder 1: 9)
- Seattle, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Publishing programs, 1960-1975. (Folder 2: 2)
  Specific names of publishers, titles of books, contracts, etc.
- Harcourt Brace and Company, Inc.--Population chapter/William A. Pullin correspondence and chapter on "Sexual Behavior,", 1956-1968 (Folder 2: 3)
- Random House, 1959-1969 (Folder 2: 4)
- Sociology Department, University of California, Berkeley, 1972 (Folder 2: 5)
- Publishers, 1960-1975 (Folder 2: 6)
- International Population and Urban Research (IPUR) business, 1970-1977 (Folder 2: 7)
- "A Structural Analysis of Kinship: Prolegomena to the Sociology of Kinship," a dissertation submitted by Kingsley Davis to the faculty of the Graduate School, Harvard University, 1936. (Folder 2: 8)
  Typescript
- Evaluation of U.S. Population Commission report, Population Association of America (PAA), 1976 April 30 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Population Research Council--Korea, 1976-1977 (Folder 3: 2)
- Speech, projection of U.S. population, sponsored by the Federal Home Loan Bank of San Francisco and Cincinnati, Ohio, University of California, Berkeley, 1976 December 7. (Folder 3: 3)
  Typescript data and letter to Kingsley Davis
- "A Crash Program for Fertility Control in Nepal," a preliminary proposal as a basis for a feasibility study to AID, Ravenholt, 1976 September (Folder 3: 4)
- Speech on U.S. population, security analysts, San Francisco, California, 1977 April 19. (Folder 3: 5)
  Correspondence and related materials
- Correspondence relating to the manuscript on "Population Policy and International Relations,", 1974 (Folder 3: 6)
- Lectures on Dialogue in Development--Concepts and Actions, 4th World Congress of Engineers and Architects, sponsored by the Association of Engineers and Architects in Israel and the International Technical Cooperation Center (I.T.C.C.), Israel, 1976 December. (Folder 3: 7)
- "The Effect of Out-Migration on Regions of Origin," chapter 10, Internal Migration: A Comparative Perspective, 1974-1976. (Folder 3: 8)
  Typescript galley proof
- "The Changing Family in Industrial Societies," paper, symposium on Health and the Family, 1976. (Folder 3: 9)
- "Social Change and Durable Social Relationships: Application of Sociological Theory to Some Contemporary Problems," speech, Chapter of Alpha Kappa Delta, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, 1976 April 21. (Folder 3: 10)
- "Population Policy and the Theory of Reproductive Motivation," revised version of a paper, Annual Meeting of the American Psychiatric Association, Detroit, Michigan, 1974. (Folder 3: 11)
- "Population," chapter revision for 4th edition, Contemporary Social Problems, 1975-1976. (Folder 3: 12)
  Typescript. Includes correspondence with Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc.
- Visiting Scholar Program, Phi Beta Kappa, Washington, D.C. Correspondence and schedule, 1975-1977 (Folder 3: 13)
- "Medicine, Mortality, and Population Change," speech, Medical Marketing Association Annual Conference, 1977 June 17. (Folder 3: 14)
- "World Population Growth and United States Foreign Aid," testimony, Committee on Appropriations, House of Representatives, United States Congress, 1977 March 31. (Folder 3: 15)
- "The Role of Urbanization in the Development Process,", undated. (Folder 3: 16)
- "Theory of Teenage Reproduction in U.S.," Belmont Conference, 1976 April. (Folder 3: 17)
  Typescript transcript
- Writings for a fiction, undated. (Folder 3: 18)
- Contract with Arno Press Inc., 1974 May (Folder 3: 19)
- National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)--Social Science--Innovative Panel records, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
- Robert Merton, 1967-1981 (Folder 4: 3-4)
- Review of "Population Growth and Land Use," Collin Clark, Scientific American, 1968 April (Folder 4: 5)
- Closing speech, Focus on Cities conference, 1968. (Folder 4: 6)
  Printed copy
- Testimony, Subcommittee on Government Research, United States Senate, 1967 June 2. (Folder 4: 7)
- "The Perilous Promise of Behavioral Science," conference, sponsored by the Subcommittee on Government Research and the Frontiers of Science Foundation of Oklahoma, Oklahoma City, 1966 October 24-27. (Folder 4: 8)
  Printed copy, Research in the Service of Man: Biomedical Knowledge, Development, and Use, 1967
- "Sozialer Wandel und internationale Beziehungen," Theorien des sozialen Wandels, Wolfgang Zapf, Neue Wissenschaftliche Bibliothek, Kiepenheuer & Witsch, 1969. Translation of original paper, "Social Change Affecting International Relations," presented at Northwestern University, International Relations Conference, 1969 April 8-10. (Folder 4: 9)
- "Population Policy: Will Current Programs Succeed?" Science, 1967 November 10. (Folder 4: 10)
- "The Climax of World Population Growth,", 1970. (Folder 4: 11)
- "Sociological Aspects of Genetic Control,", 1966. (Folder 4: 12)
- "La Comparación Internacionál en las Ciencias Sociales Problems y Soluciones,", 1965. (Folder 4: 13)
  Typescript. Translation of "Problems and Solutions in International Comparison for Social Science Purposes"
- "Conceptual Aspects of Urban Projections in Developing Countries," Proceedings of the World Population Conference, 1965. (Folder 4: 14)
- "Demography," paper, National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), Committee on Social and Cultural Processes, 1972. (Folder 4: 15)
- Testimony, Subcommittee on Census and Statistics of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service, House of Representatives, United States Congress, San Francisco, California, 1969 May 19. (Folder 4: 16)
- "Politica de Población: Tendrán Éxito Los Programas Actuales?" Demografía y Economía, 1969. (Folder 4: 17)
- "World Urbanization and Economic Development," Proceedings of the Focus on Cities Conference, 1968. (Folder 4: 18)
- "Will Family Planning Solve the Population Problem?" Victor-Bostrom Fund for the International Planned Parenthood Federation, 1968 Fall. (Folder 4: 19)
- Biography material, 1977-1980 (Folder 4: 20)
- Course materials, undated (Box-folder 5: 1-3)
- Notebooks, undated (Folder 5: 4)
- Collection of writings by others, 1926-1929 (Folder 5: 5)
- Countries for population study (Box 6)
  - Ceylon, 1960 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Costa Rica, 1963-1964 (Folder 6: 2-3)
  - Egypt, 1963 (Folder 6: 4)
  - El Salvador, 1964 (Folder 6: 5-6)
  - France, 1951-1963 (Folder 6: 7)
  - French Guiana, 1976 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Guatemala, 1964-1999 (Folder 6: 9-10)
  - Honduras, 1966 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Ireland, undated (Folder 6: 12)
  - North America, undated (Folder 6: 13)
  - South America, undated (Folder 6: 14)
  - Syria, undated (Folder 6: 15)
  - Taiwan, 1957-1980 (Folder 6: 16)
  - Thailand, 1960 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Tunisia, undated (Folder 6: 18)
  - Turkey, 1957-1958 (Folder 6: 19)
- Country data sheets, 1958 (Folder 6: 20)
- Course materials, undated (Folder 6: 21)
- University of California bio-bibliography (Box 7)
  - 1973-1974 (Folder 7: 1)
  - 1974-1975 (Folder 7: 2)
  - 1975-1976 (Folder 7: 3)
  - 1976-1977 (Folder 7: 4)
  - 1977-1978 (Folder 7: 5)
- Autobiographical material, International Who's Who, 1974-1975 (Folder 7: 6)
- California Legislature--Assembly Science Technology Advisory Committee (ASTAC), 1973 (Folder 7: 7)
- American Sociological Association section on the Sociology of Population, 1973-1977 (Folder 7: 8-9)
- Requests for reprints of Kingsley Davis's "Population Policy: Will Current Program Succeed?" (Folder 7: 10)
- Countries for population study
  - Ireland, 1950-1963 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Italy and Malta, 1963 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Japan, 1963 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Mauritius, 1963 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Nicaragua, 1967 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Panama, 1967 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Portugal, 1950-1963 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Spain, 1947-1963 (Folder 7: 18)
  - United Kingdom
    - General, 1957-1958. (Folder 7: 19)
      Typescript chapters on metropolitan expansion in England and Wales, data sheets, and notes
    - London (folder empty) (Folder 7: 20)
  - U.S.S.R., 1975-1980 (Folder 7: 21-22)
  - Venezuela, 1957-1974 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Vietnam, 1959 (Folder 7: 24)
  - West Indies, 1956(?) (Folder 7: 25)
  - Yugoslavia, 1958-1960 (Folder 7: 26)
  - Zambia, 1975 (Folder 7: 27)
  - Zanzibar, 1959 (Folder 7: 28)
- Correspondence (Box 8)
  - A, 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 1)
  - B, 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 2)
  - C, 1974-1977 (Folder 8: 3)
  - D, 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 4)
  - E, 1976-1977 (Folder 8: 5)
  - F, 1976 (Folder 8: 6)
  - G, 1975-1976 (Folder 8: 7)
  - H, 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 8)
  - I, 1975-1976 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Berkov, Beth, 1976-1977 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Das Gupta, Prithwis, 1973-1976 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Davis, Judith Blake, 1977 (vitae) (Folder 8: 12)
  - Oever, Nelle Van Den, 1977 May (Folder 8: 13)
  - Rankin, Robert, 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Social Demography, 1976 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Stone, Linda, 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 16)
  - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), (Grusky), 1976 (Folder 8: 17)
- Sabbatical leave and retirement, 1973-1976 (Folder 8: 18)
- Consulting jobs, 1974-1977 (Folder 8: 19)
- Job offers, 1974-1977 (Folder 8: 20)
- Arrangements: Van Arsdol, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, 1976-1977 (Folder 8: 21)
- TV/radio interviews, 1973 (Folder 8: 22)
- Bibliography and requests, 1973-1977 (Folder 8: 23-25)
- Biographical information
  - Undated (Folder 8: 26)
  - 1975-1977 (Folder 8: 27)
- Writings by others (Box 9)
  - B-J, 1948-1963 (Folder 9: 1)
  - K-W, 1931-1963 (Folder 9: 2)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1973. (Folder 9: 3)
  Correspondence
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences (AAAS), 1974-1977. (Folder 9: 4)
  Includes correspondence and related materials
- Correspondence, J-Z, 1975-1977 (Folder 9: 5-16)
- "Human Populations," lecture, Carlton University, Ottawa, Canada, 1972 June 2. (Box-folder 10: 1)
- "Divorce and Welfare in California," application, proposal, and worksheets for a study, 1976-1978. (Folder 10: 2-4)
  Includes correspondence
- Correspondence
  - Greenwood Press, 1974-1977, and contract, 1974-1975 (Folder 10: 5-6)
  - W. H. Freeman and Company Ltd., 1977 (Folder 10: 7)
- Reprint fees received, 1976 (Folder 10: 8)
- Travel and honorarium claims and checks, 1974-1976 (Folder 10: 9)
- "Urbanization," Universitas, Salvat Editores, S. A., Barcelona, Spain, 1971-1972. (Folder 10: 10)
  Typescript. Includes a version in English and a galley proof in Spanish
- "Asia and World Population," to appear in a reader edited by Elliot Tepper, 1972 June. (Folder 10: 11)
- "Population Policy: Will Current Programs Succeed?" Science, 1967 November. (Folder 10: 12)
- Holograph notes on national character, undated (Folder 10: 13)
- Writings by others, A-S, 1948-1959 (Folder 10: 14-15)
- "Reflections on Urbanization and Social Stratification," manuscript to be published in a Festschrift volume to be titled Stability and Change in Social System: Essays in Honor of Talcott Parsons, 1970. (Box-folder 11: 1)
- Correspondence
  - University of California, Berkeley (campus), 1974-1976 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Sociology Department, University of California, Berkeley, 1975-1977 (Folder 11: 3)
- University of California and Nepal for the Family Planning/Material and Child Health (FP/MCH) Project, 1976-1977. (Folder 11: 4-5)
  Includes report and correspondence
- International Population and Urban Research (on campus), (IPUR), 1969-1976 (Folder 11: 6)
- Dean, Graduate Division, University of California, Berkeley, 1976-1977 (Folder 11: 7)
- Greenwood Press, 1975-1977 (Folder 11: 8)
- Berkov manuscript--rough copies--meeting with Jane(?) and Beth, 1976 January 13 (Folder 11: 9)
- Sociology Department, University of California, Berkeley--General, 1974-1976 (Folder 11: 10)
- "Divorce and Welfare in California," final version, 1976-1979
  - Proposal for grant, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1976-1979 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Proposal, 1977 August. (Folder 11: 12)
    Includes correspondence with Robert Rankin
- "Child Welfare and Illegitimate Reproduction: The California Case," co-authored with Susan DeVos, 1977 August. (Folder 11: 13)
  Typescript. Includes contract, 1970-1975
- Participant, California Policy Seminar, sponsored by the University of California, Berkeley, 1974-1977 (Folder 11: 14-15)
- "Mother's Age," proposal for continuing research, 1977-1978 (Folder 11: 16)
- Proposal submitted to Department of Benefit Payments, State of California, for funding based on the pre-proposal, "Divorce and Welfare in California," 1976 August - September. Includes a request for approval of the Committee for Protection of Human Subjects, 1976 October (Folder 11: 17-18)
- "Urbanization in the Light of Contemporary Population Change," participant, faculty seminar, Harvard University, 1966 April 27 (Box-folder 12: 1)
- "Some Demographic Aspects of Poverty," speech, Poverty in America Conference, University of California, Berkeley, 1965 February 28. (Folder 12: 2)
- "Urbanization of the Human Population," Scientific American, 1965 September. (Folder 12: 3)
- "Conceptual Aspects of Urban Projections in Developing Countries," World Population Conference, Belgrade, Yugoslavia, 1965 August 30 - September 10. (Folder 12: 4)
- Messenger Lecture, Cornell University, 1963 Fall. (Folder 12: 5)
- "Demographic and Social Change in Next Twenty-Five Years," paper, Proceedings of the Sixth World Conference of the Society for International Development, Washington, D.C., 1964 March 16-18. (Folder 12: 6)
- "Norms, Values, and Sanctions," chapter in Handbook of Modern Sociology, 1964-1965. (Folder 12: 7)
- "Facts and the Future," Mission of the Church in a World of Cities, Scientific American, 1965. (Folder 12: 8)
- "Problems and Solutions in International Comparison for Social Science Purposes," translation of "La Comparacion Internacional en las Ciencias Sociales: Problemas y Soluciones," America Latin, 1965 January - March. (Folder 12: 9)
  Typescript and printed copy
- "The Theory of Change and Response in Modern Demographic History," Population Index, Population Association of America meeting, Philadelphia, 1963 April. (Folder 12: 10)
- "Sociological Consequences of Advanced Reproductive Control," American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) meeting, Cleveland, Ohio, 1963 December 28. (Folder 12: 11)
- "The Place of Latin America in World Demographic History," paper, Milbank Memorial Conference, Milbank Memorial Fund, 1963 September 17-18. (Folder 12: 12)
  Typescript notes of discussion of Miró and Martens' papers at the conference. Includes a typescript paper, "Population Growth and Population Policy," undated
- "Population," Scientific American, 1963 September. (Folder 12: 13)
- "Sociological Aspect of Genetic Control," chapter, Genetics and the Future of Man, 1966 (Folder 12: 14)
- Contributions to Urban Research in the Modern Urban Revolution, 1963. (Folder 12: 15)
  Correspondence and notes
- "Urbanization: Changing Patterns of Living," The Changing American Population, 1962. (Folder 12: 16)
- "The Early Marriage Trend," What's New, 1958 Fall. (Folder 12: 17)
- Human Society, 1949. (Folder 12: 18)
- "Parent-Youth Conflict: A Sociological Interpretation," Marriage, Family, and Society, 1940. (Folder 12: 19)
- "Asia and World Population,", 1972(?). (Folder 12: 20)
- Testimony, Subcommittee on Government Research, Committee on Government Operations, U.S. Senate, 1967 June 2. (Folder 12: 21)
- Material from Human Society for Role Theory: Concepts and Research, Edwin J. Thomas and Bruce J. Biddle, 1963-1966, undated (Folder 12: 22)
  Includes typescript manuscripts "Social Norms: Classification of Norms" and "Status and Related Concepts: Identity within the Situation," and correspondence, 1963-1966
- Las Causas y Efectos del Fenomeno de Primacia Urbana Con Referencia Especial a America Latina," ("The Causes and Effects of First-City, Primacy with Special Reference to Latin America"), Mexico, 1962 November. (Folder 12: 23)
  Typescript in Spanish and English
- Alice Harris (case # 199), 1938-1949. (Box-folder 13: 1-3)
  Includes photographs
- "Final note on a Case of Extreme Isolation,", 1938-1947. (Folder 13: 4)
  Typescript drafts
- Isolation--Comparative notes and literature, 1900-1966. (Folder 13: 5)
  Typescript and holograph notes
- Agnes Hunt, 1938-1939 (Folder 13: 6)
- Ann Barton, 1946 (Folder 13: 7)
- "World Organization and Economic Development," Focus on Cities Conference, Durban, South Africa, 1968 July 6-15. (Folder 13: 8)
- "The Perilous Promise of Behavioral Science," revised from the conference sponsored by the Subcommittee on Government Research and the Frontiers of Science Foundation, Oklahoma, 1966 October 24-27. (Folder 13: 9)
  Typescript. Includes a printed copy, Research in the Service of Man: Biomedical Knowledge, Development and Use, 1967
- "The Quest for Security in Sociological and Demographic Perspective," chapter in Man's Quest for Security, 1966. (Folder 13: 10)
- Comments on Kingsley Davis's publications, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 14: 1)
- Comments on "Population Policy: Will Current Programs Succeed?" Science, 1967 November (Folder 14: 2)
- "Jealousy and Sexual Property." (Folder 14: 3)
  Typescript. Includes a printed copy, Human Society, 1949, revised 1976
- NATO Science Committee 20th Anniversary Commemoration meeting, Brussels, Belgium, 1978 April 11-13. (Folder 14: 4)
- Collection of papers on sociology by Kingsley Davis(?), undated. (Folder 14: 5)
- Lists of publications from International Population and Urban Research, Institute of International Studies, University of California, Berkeley, 1965-1974 (Folder 14: 6)
- Report of the Conference on Population Problems, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1952 June 20-22, prepared by John Hajnal-Konyi, 1952 November (Folder 14: 7)
- Report and articles, 1974-1977. (Folder 14: 8)
  Includes "Implications on UN Population Policy," Rick Kranenburg, 1975; Evaluation of U.S. Population Commission report, 1976 April 30; and "Biosocial Feedback Mechanism in Human Population Growth," Kingsley Davis, undated. Includes related correspondence, 1974-1977
- Private book review, 1929-1930 (Folder 14: 9)
- Rann proposal for funding from National Science Foundation for the project "Bio-Genetic Implications of Demographic Change,", 1972 September 1 (Box-folder 15: 1)
- Notes from Resseguie, undated. (Folder 15: 2)
- "Illegitimacy" project, 1970-1973 (Folder 15: 3)
- International Population and Urban Research (IPUR), University of California, Berkeley, progress report, 1956-1962
- Data on population by states
  - Alaska--by previous children and sex and by race and age of mother, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Colorado--by county, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Connecticut--by county, and age and color of mother, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Delaware--by county and race, 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 7)